Now some of the parts that you might add to your winter horse blanket are called hoods and neck covers.
Now hoods usually go down over their face so let me show you this.
This one doesn't necessarily go with this blanket but will just show you how it works. It slides up over the top of their head and then comes down thru their ears and they can see through it there we go so it would fit down over their face.
Now you'd say why do I need a hood for my horse.
People that want that show quality shine like a lot halter horses and performance horses, show horses they want to keep them in their short hair coats all over their body all winter long so that they can keep showing them and have that summer look to them it shows off their body better.
So their going to purchase a hood that covers all their body.
It doesn't do much good if you're showing a horse to have him smooth and shiny up to right here and then his chest and head is hairy cause then you're going to need to body clip that and once you body clip it he's going to be cold there and then you're going to need to apply a hood.
Now this a net cover.
This net cover will go right over the top of the head and then the blanket has buckles and the neck cover has straps.
So what we're going to do is just need apply the straps to the blanket and secure the neck cover in place.
Why would your horse need a neck cover?
Well if he's outside and it rains a lot or snows a lot on him the blanket might be waterproof but the problem is that sometimes it rains or snows on their neck and melts and it can still get down into your blanket.
So you might have a waterproof blanket but if you don't have a neck cover it won't keep it from running down their neck into the horses blanket.
Then it secures with fasteners in the front as well.
So, that if he starts playing or running around it's pretty secure to the blanket and also in the front.
Some of the hoods or net covers will have a strap that attaches to a halter so it's got even more strength for moving around.
So this net cover is going to keep him pretty much covered from the elements from his neck and it won't allow any of the moisture to get down inside his blanket and run down into or on his chest or inside the blanket.
So that's why you would use a net cover to keep their hair coat short or to keep out the elements from inside their blanket.